# Wayne W. Grigsby III

Technology Consultant





grigswa@gmail.com



Washington DC



# PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

My experiences over the past 7 years have given me the knowledge to both comprehend and converse on almost all things related to technology. Whether I am leading a project team, developing solutions, or building consensus, I have always exceeded expectations. I thrive in high-pressure situations and relish the opportunity to own tasks, projects, and products. No matter what I do, I continue to bring the high level of excitement, hard work, knowledge, and common sense I have come to be known for.

# SKILLS

Attention to Detail
Strong Interpersonal Skills
Strong Communication Skills
Team Leadership
Project Planning
Agile Methodology
Process Improvement
Customer Service
Resource Management
Project Management
Quantitative Analysis
Qualitative Analysis
Creativity
Writing

# **EDUCATION**

BACHELORS DEGREE Political Science Columbus State University

# **CLEARANCE**

Available upon request

# **EXPERIENCE**

INDEPENDENT TECHNOLOGY CONSULTANT October 2016 - Present

As an independent consultant abroad, I have provided my experience and expertise to Interpol. I have also continued providing my expertise and advice to stateside organizations regarding their technology. During this time I taught myself python while at the same time fine tuning my web design/developer skills.

- Analyzed Interpol processes and provided recommendations for improvement
- Provided individual recommendations to Interpol employees regarding the benefits of migrating away from antiquated technologies to modern solutions
- Repaired and deployed VBA scripts for Interpol General Secretariat (IPSG)
- Trained Interpol employees how to use new scripts and analyze data
- Developed Python scripts to manage financial transactions
- Utilized APIs to pull currency data and provide financial transactions an accurate conversion
- Developed Django website to house financial tracking app
- Utilized Git to track the history of my code
- Redeveloped Python financial code to operate within the Django web framework
- Utilized bootstrap 3 and developed custom css to design Django website for desktop/mobile
- Deployed Django apps on Heroku
- Manage and maintain postgresql server

### TECHNOLOGY ANALYST

Booz Allen Hamilton | Office of the Secretary of Defense | June 2016 - October 2016

Within the Office of the Secretary Defense, the Business Process Systems Review (BPSR) staff focuses on efficiencies and new emerging technological capabilities. As a Technology Analyst for the BPSR office, I focused my efforts on enabling the Department of Defense with technology while working within the known budgetary constraints. Researching and analyzing costs, potential savings, and returns on investment were integral to providing the Government with viable solutions to their enterprise issues.

- Analyzed software capabilities and costs in parallel with allotted budget to provide leadership with viable solutions
- Served as a liaison between the Government, industry, and contract teams
- Engaged industry in an effort to discuss and deliver solutions to complex

# Wayne Grigsby | Technology Consultant





grigswa@gmail.com



Washington DC



# TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML & CSS

Python

Diango

Heroku

Javascript

Postgresal

**SQLite** 

MAC, Windows, LINUX Microsoft SharePoint

SharePoint Designer

Adobe Photoshop

**VSphere** 

**PyCharm** 

GitHub

WordPress

# CERTIFICATIONS & TRAINING

ITIL V3 Certification ISO
Introduction to Python
20000:1 Foundations CompTIA
A+ Certification
Administering SharePoint
Windows Server & AD
FSO Management
SharePoint Designer

### **EXPERIENCE** continued

- Served as a liaison between the Government, industry, and contract teams
- Managed software demos and analyzed data output with a focus on potential process impact
- Engaged industry in an effort to discuss and deliver solutions to complex enterprise issues
- Reviewed and edited new capability proposals, storyboards, and use cases to consolidate technological realities with expected outcomes
- Collaborated with industry experts to determine ways in which the Government could effectively utilize new and emerging technologies
- Coordinated industry outreach efforts in support of DOD technology requirements
- Managed Senior Executive Service (SES) officials and provided task deliverable support in an effort to provide maximum efficiency and availability of BPSR leadership

### **TECHNOLOGY STRATEGIST**

Booz Allen Hamilton | Joint Chiefs of Staff | August 2014 - June 2016

As a member of the Information Management Division of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, I managed a multitude of technology, process improvement, and knowledge management projects. My mission was to enhance the usage of collaborative tools and applications among Joint Staff members and partners. These efforts enabled the Joint Staff to efficiently communicate and collaborate with Combatant Commands and successfully execute the agenda of the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.

- Translated complex technological concepts to the government client in an effort to spread information and knowledge
- Developed strategies for achieving information management, knowledge management, and information technology goals
- Performed analysis of IT programs, business processes, and technology policy
- Solely cleared a 3 year project backlog within 6 months
- Served as a liaison between technology teams, government personnel, and vendors
- Developed SharePoint solutions to enhance the availability and accountability of staff members and their data
- Provided recommendations, guidance, and counsel to leadership regarding technology concepts and policy to enhance decision making

### SYSTEMS ANALYST

Mymic LLC | Joint Chiefs of Staff | September 2013 - August 2014

As an analyst for the Joint Staff IT Department, I worked closely with every office to ensure the usage and understanding of the Joint Staff's collaborative tools remained optimal. I led multiple efforts to enhance web sites and to develop SharePoint applications. I also worked with government clients to analyze existing processes in an effort to determine a more efficient way, utilizing technology, to enhance these processes.

- Provided technology, business process and knowledge management recommendations and support to the Joint Staff and its components
- Designed enterprise solutions that utilized authoritative data sources within the Joint Staff environment
- Led efforts to plan and implement enterprise-level pilots, data calls, migrations and transitions
- Evaluated vendor products per the organization's budget and business requirements
- Designed and developed SharePoint solutions to meet the requirements of Joint Staff users

# Wayne Grigsby | Technology Consultant





grigswa@gmail.com



Washington DC



# LINKS

Website Github Linkedin

# **EXPERIENCE** continued

- Served as the sole point of contact for the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff's office in all Technology matters
- Designed and developed SharePoint solutions to meet the requirements of Joint Staff users
- Utilized HTML, CSS, and JAVASCRIPT to design and develop SharePoint sites

#### LEAD IT SPECIALIST

Knight Point Systems | October 2011 - September 2013

As the sole IT resource in a newly-established IT department, I developed and managed all IT assets, processes, and company certifications for three rapidly growing companies (300+ employees). I significantly upgraded and advanced the technology and performance of the companies' IT systems while working within the constraints of a limited budget. Additionally, I successfully balanced the roles of systems/network administrator, security officer, help desk, and ISO 20000 quality manager.

- Developed methodologies on a situational basis to increase the performance and reliability of the network and system's infrastructure
- Successfully completed and passed 3 annual ISO 20000:1 audits
- Designed and developed a company service catalog to track all IT assets and associated documentation
- Developed and maintained change management, risk management, and content management policies
- Designed and developed a custom ticketing system within SharePoint to track all issues, risks, and changes
- Successfully completed 3 annual security audits to maintain the company's facility clearance
- Developed and implemented IT security practices and policies in the management and administration of the company infrastructure
- Administered networks, servers, and VOIP services
- Planned and led multiple software, hardware, and service provider upgrades/ transitions

### HELP DESK TECHNICIAN

TEKsystems/HQ Dept. of the Army | March 2011 - October 2011

As a help desk technician, I exceeded all performance expectations and goals set by leadership. I maintained the highest call level to issue resolution ratio among the staff. I also earned a solid reputation for resolving complex issues while also providing excellent customer service.

- Analyzed problems and generated action reports in an effort to resolve issues as quickly as possible
- Regularly performed software maintenance
- Utilized multiple military and civilian databases
- Led training sessions with fellow employees to demonstrate skills and
- techniques that helped resolve incidents and issues